

□ (+1) 865-368-8485 | ■ me@cade.site | A cade.site/about | □ cadebrown | □ cade-brown | ■ @dev\_ceb

# **Summary**\_

Hey! I'm Cade Brown and I'm a computer science researcher. My main areas of research are:

- Machine Learning (ML): theory, implementation, and deployment of neural networks
- High-Performance Computing (HPC): distributed/parallel programming and optimization
- Numerical programming and linear algebra, specifically on GPUs and distributed systems
- Computer Vision (CV): algorithms and methods for visual processing

Additionally, I also experience and interest in **Human-Computer Interaction (HCI)**, **Programming Language Theory (PLT)**, and robotics. I'm interested in applying mathematical modeling and computing to solve problems in a wide range of fields that it gets difficult to list, so check out my blog for more information: **cade.site/blog**.

Outside of my professional interests, I have personal interests in novel approaches to digital art (ML-generated, data-driven art), philosophy (AI ethics, metaphysics), and all kinds of music. If any of these things interest you (professionally or personally), drop me a line at: **me@cade.site**.

# **Publications**

#### Design, Optimization, and Benchmarking of Dense Linear Algebra Algorithms on AMD GPUs

(Remote)

CADE BROWN, A. ABDELFATTAH, S. TOMOV, J. DONGARRA

2021-09

- Ported and performance tuned the MAGMA linear algebra library for AMD GPUs (60x faster for some BLAS, 73% faster Eigensolvers)
- IEEE HPEC 2020: ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9286214

#### Surrogate ML/AI Model Benchmarking for FAIR Principles' Conformance

(Remote) 2022-09

P. Luszczek, Cade Brown

• IEEE HPEC 2022 (pending)

## **SMCEFR: Sentinel-3 Satellite Dataset**

Oak Ridge, TN, USA

CADE BROWN, P. LUZSCZEK

2022-07

- This dataset was sponsored for the ORNL Smoky Mountain Conference, as a data challenge for other researchers
- · URL: cade.site/smcefr

# Talks\_

# **TuneSM: Autotuning GPU Kernels With Cortex**

(Remote)

CADE BROWN @ NVIDIA (INTERNAL)

2022

• Overview of my project at NVIDIA, using ML models to optimize other ML models. (under NDA)

#### **SABATH: ML Surrogate Platform**

(Remote)

CADE BROWN @ MLCOMMONS SCIENCE

2022

• Demonstrated the SABATH layer for ML model reproducibility in scientific applications to MLCommons Science

# **Challenge #6: Sentinel-3 Satellite Dataset**

Oak Ridge, TN, USA

CADE BROWN @ SMOKY MOUNTAIN CONFERENCE (ORNL)

2022

• Introduced the SMCEFR dataset and data challenge questions for researchers at Smoky Mountain Conference at ORNL

## MAGMA -> hipMAGMA: Adding HIP Compatibility To A Scientific C++ Library

Knoxville, TN, USA

CADE BROWN @ ICL ANNUAL CONFERENCE

2018

• Demonstrated how HIP can be used on traditional CUDA scientific libraries to produce portable code that runs on AMD GPUs

# **Program Committees**

2022 **Dataset Sponsor**, 2022 Smoky Mountain Conference (ORNL)

Oak Ridge, TN, USA

**Experience** 

## **Innovative Computing Lab @ UTK**

Knoxville, TN, USA

2022

HPC Research Assistant 2019-

- Accelerating High-Performance-Computing (HPC) workloads for BLAS and LAPACK libraries targeting supercomputers
- Developing scientific machine learning platform for reproducibility of scientific surrogate models using FAIR principles
- Porting and performance tuning numerical linear algebra routines for diverse hardware (CPU, GPU, Multi-GPU, ...)

• Used: CUDA, C/C++, Fortran, Python, MPI, OpenMP, HIP/ROCm, DPC++/OneAPI, PyTorch

NVIDIA (Remote)

COMPILER RESEARCH INTERN

- Accelerating training and inference of machine learning models (LLMs, CNNs, etc) with research compilers
- Improved GPU kernel code generation for tensor operations using polyhedral compilation techniques
- Created ML-assisted code optimization and autotuning framework to improve selection heuristics
- Used: CUDA, C/C++, Python, LLVM/MLIR, NumPy, PyTorch, Tensorflow, Matplotlib

PAIRS Lab @ UTK
HCI RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Knoxville, TN, USA
2021-2022

• **Developed research prototypes** of developer productivity software aimed at automated error solving

- Evaluated and improved graph database queries for terabyte-scale dataset of source code for analytics
- Used: Java, Python, REST, ArangoDB

Qardian Labs Knoxville, TN, USA

MACHINE LEARNING CONSULTANT

2020

- Developed a machine learning model for automated detection of heart health anomalies, given key metrics
- Deployed a web application for healthcare professionals to use the model
- · Used: Python, Tensorflow, Django, Heroku

# Oak Ridge National Lab (ORNL)

Oak Ridge, TN, USA

RESEARCH INTERN 2017-2018

- Developed interactive scientific simulations running in real-time in a distributed cluster computer (SimpleSummit/Bubbles)
- Aided in physical fabrication for the cluster computer design, 3D-printed by MDF to hold 8x NVIDIA Jetsons
- Implemented and ran benchmarks to measure scalability of the Lustre parallel filesystem on Titan supercomputer
- · Used: C/C++, CUDA, Python, MPI, SDL, Blender
- · URL: simplesummit.github.io

## Free Software Foundation (FSF/GNU)

(Remote)

**OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTOR** 

2016-2017

- Implemented arbitrary precision arithmetic for scientific functions in MPFR
- Assisted other researchers in mailing lists for problems encountered
- URL: mpfr.org

Agilaire LLC Knoxville, TN, USA

SOFTWARE CONSULTANT

- Designed and implemented pilog, a Raspberry Pi data logger and server that records and reports air quality metrics
- Lead and architected the programming department, consisting of 3-5 other developers
- Used: Java, Python, OpenCV, hardware

# **Education**

# University of Tennesee Knoxville (UTK) BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Knoxville, TN, USA

2019-2023\*

• FIRST Robotics Alumni Scholarship

- Trav Drawn Engine aring Cabalarah
- Trey Brown Engineering Scholarship
- Col. Lockett Engineering Scholarship
- UT Volunteer Scholarship

# **Projects**

# kscript: a dynamic programming language

Knoxville, TN, USA

CADE BROWN

2018-2020

- This is a programming language I wrote from scratch, similar to Python but faster for some things and a better syntax
- Used: C/C++, Python, GMP, FFTW, FFMPEG/libav\*, WebAssembly (WASM), GNU readline
- URL: kscript.org | term.kscript.org (online REPL) | docs.kscript.org (documentation)

Knoxville, TN, USA

CADE BROWN 2021

• This is a C compiler (well, a subset of C) that I wrote for a compilers class to update the teacher's example to use modern LLVM and C++ constructs

- Supports external linking, arrays, functions, and can implement matrix multiplication, cat program, and more examples
- Used: C/C++, LLVM/JIT
- URL: github.com/cadebrown/mycc

#### **Blok: Minecraft-style Game From Scratch**

Knoxville, TN, USA

CADE BROWN

2020

- I wrote this from scratch to show how to make a Minecraft-style voxel game from scratch, including world generation, chunk rendering, mesh generation, input, and so forth in C/C++
- Used: OpenGL, GLFW, AssImp, FreeType, PortAudio
- URL: github.com/cadebrown/blok

#### **CARVE: Cade Andgreg's RISC-V Emulator**

Knoxville, TN, USA

CADE BROWN, GREGORY CROISDALE

2020

- · A free web IDE to run and debug RISC-V assembly, with memory/stack explorer and helpful hints
- Used: C/C++, Python, JavaScript, HTML/CSS, WebAssembly (WASM), RISC-V
- · URL: carve.cade.site

#### My Research/Personal Blog

Knoxville, TN, USA

**CADE BROWN** 

2015-

- My online presence, including blog posts, papers, diagrams, and more
- URL: cade.site/blog

#### **Semi-Autonomous Robot Design**

Knoxville, TN, USA

FIRST ROBOTICS #3966

2015-2018

- I was the lead programmer on my robotics team, which included design and implementation of semi-autonomous robots that compete against other teams.
- · Video: cade.site/robotvideo